## Jose Miguel García

LOCATION

Envigado, Antioquia

**PHONE** 

+57 (305) 357-3300

E-MAIL

josepplloo@gmail.com

WFB

linkedin.com/in/josem-garciag github.com/josepplloo

**REFERENCES** 

Any Ruiz Web Engineer at Huge anyruiz@hugeinc.com

OSCAR ORTEGA
Professor at UdeA

oscar.ortega@udea.edu.co

## Profile

Informatics engineer and student of MSc. in software engineering with over four years of experience mainly as a consultant and backend developer, as well as research experience in machine learning and data mining. Currently, decided to change career into frontend development and user experience.

## Experience

JULY 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

SUMMAN S.A.S

Development Engineer

Build, deliver and support Redhat enterprise solutions for regional

customers.

MARCH 2016 – CURRENT UNIVERSITY OF ANTIOQUIA

Lecturer

Introduction to Systems Engineering

course.

JANUARY 2012 – JUNE 2015 SUMMA

SUMMAN S.A.S

Development Analyst

Development of new documents for Summan DataVar and integration of data among information silos using Pentaho

and Fuse ESB.

Skills

LANGUAGES English (60%), Spanish (100%)

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES, SOFTWARE AND FRAMEWORKS

Javascript, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, Docker, SQL, Git, JBoss, Maven, Red Hat

and Scrum.

METHODOLOGIES AND

PRACTICES

Agile, CI/CD, Hefesto, Software design

patterns.

Education

AUGUST 2015 - 2019

UNIVERSITY OF ANTIOQUIA

MSc in software engineering

FEBRUARY 2006 – APRIL 2015

JAIME ISAZA CADAVID COLOMBIAN

POLYTECHNIC

Engineer's degree - Informatics Engineer

## **Projects**

**G**UIDE TO INDUSTRY ADOPTION OF SOFTWARE PRODUCT LINES

DECEMBER 2015 - AUGUST 2017

Product catalog or portfolio is a tool to communicate the minimal capacity of production in the product line, the aim in this book chapter was figure out how the main concepts inside this technology can help to construct a minimum viable product.

PRODUCT: Incremental Definition of Product Catalog for a Product Line in Guide to industry adoption of software product lines. https://goo.gl/d29dFt

CONFORMATION, EVOLUTION AND CONSISTENCY BASED ON THE CONCEPT OF PRODUCT LINE IN ORGANIZATIONS AND DATA MINING SOLUTIONS NOVEMBER 2015 – FEBRUARY 2016

Development of a review for the technics of data mining in order to modeling Product lines.